

POL SURRIEL

Software Engineer

psurrielm@gmail.com

+34 601 08 30 31

linkedin.com/in/psurriel







CAREER SUMMARY

Hi, I'm Pol Surriel. Software developer with experience in IT Project Management. For me, a deep understanding of the culture, values, and infrastructure of an organization is essential to achieve efficient integration, productivity, and communication. I present good algorithmic problem solving, fast error diagnosis, a very high level of proactivity and enthusiasm, human contact, and ease of creating and conceptualizing complex software structures. Along my career I have been involved in many teams and production processes. My technical stack is strong in videogame development aspects such as complex AI behaviours, graphics programming and gameplay programming within procedural animations. My second strength is web developement. I'm passionate about math and never stop learning.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Teacher of Unity, Kotlin, Android & Project mentor

Institut Tecnològic de Barcelona

2021 - Present

At ITB I'm in charge of instructing my students in technologies such as Unity, Android Studio, basic programming (Kotlin) and P5js. I also am a mentor and tribunal member for projects that require a high mathematical load. One of my best contributions has been to modify the syllabus by adding content on the internal workings of game engines, advanced optimization techniques and implementation techniques for behavioral Als.

Technologies used:



Co-Founder, Junior producer & developer (C#, CGPROGRAM)

Surreal Boost

2019 - Present

Along with this project I have been in charge of two different teams (formed by 8 and 5 people respectively). My development tasks were in graphics programming, gameplay programming and complex behavioral Als. More of my main functions were the constant analysis of the production process to design of organizational changes, scope or dev techniques. Therefore I am very familiar with leading agile ceremonies and proactively proposing changes to improve efficiency.

Achievements:

- Proactively negotiate with more than 10 external stakeholders, obtaining direct access to incubation programs and grants, mentorships from important companies like LinceWorks and under-NDA AAA company.
- Reduce the risk deduction of investment by generatic a healthy development process history and actively participating in the business plan development.
- Develop scalable, with quality code and documentation products.
- Recruit and lead a cross-functional high-performance team.

Technologies used:



Java back-end developer (Intern)

SIGMA: Helping Universities Succeed

2018

Durgin my Internship at SIGMA I mainly worked in Java Backend projects adding new features or fixing bugs. It ended with a job offer, but I wanted to start my Engineering degree and IT Project Management Posgrade.

Technologies used:

Java Maven jQuery Bootstrap

HTML/CSS Angular 6 JS/TS, JSP

SKILLS & TOOLS

Frontend Angular Typescript/JavaScript Bootstrap HTML/CSS/SASS Game development Unity C++ Unreal Unity Shaders **Others** Gitflow Git Unit Testing Python Agile After Effects Photoshop Phaser SQL Firebase Storytelling

EDUCATION

Engineering in Digital Interactive Content Degree

ENTI (School of Interactive New Technologies), Universitat de Barcelona 2018 - present (75% of credits)

Posgrade in IT Project Management

Gimbernat, Universitat Autonoma de Barcelona Grade: 10 2018 - 2019

DAW - Web developement, (CFGS / Vocational studies)

Institut Jaume Balmes Grade: 8 2016 - 2018

SMX - Microcomputer systems, (CFGM/Vocational studies)

Institut Jaume Balmes Grade: 8 2014 - 2016

WORK EXPERIENCE



Front-end web developer

IndianWebs

2016

During my stand on IndianWebs I used to directly talk with the clients, understanding the needs of their projects and discussed with the team how would be proceed with te developement of more than 15 web projects.

Technologies used:









PROJECTS AND ACTIVITY

An important part of my projects's code are under non discloursemnt agreements. Due to this, an part of my portfolio are explanations of important features or challenges that I have faced.

Megaman 2 Remake Vertical Slice (Phaser.js)

Project Management Sheets link0.cv.psurriel.com

Github project link1.cv.psurriel.com

SYNAPSE: A Unity Project (C#, CGPROGRAM)

Gameplay main character link2.cv.psurriel.com

Rendering feature: main character VFX and material rendering

link3.cv.psurriel.com

Rendering feature: Multiversal stains.

link4.cv.psurriel.com

Multiplayer state sincronization (Post)

Twitter thead

link5.cv.psurriel.com

C++ cloth simulation project (Project overview)

Twitter thead link5.cv.psurriel.com

Pellets.io: A non-library JS online game (JS + Node.js)

Trailer

link6.cv.psurriel.com

Gameplay

link7.cv.psurriel.com

Editor at 3DJuegos.com

Article example link8.cv.psurriel.com

Grestner waves formulas (Post)

Linkedin post

link9.cv.psurriel.com

Digital Helheim: Linear Algebra and Geometry (Project)

Github project

link10.cv.psurriel.com

Cijestone.com

Website cijestone.com

AWARDS

Q Best student Scolarship 2018

UAB/SIGMA: Helping Universities Suceed

 Honors in Agile methodologies ENTI-UB

2020

LANGUAGE

English (Professional)

Spanish (Native)

Catalan (Native)

INTERESTS

Project management

Soft skills

Machine learning

Physics simulations



Eduardo Zaldivar Back-end Software Engineer

at Netcentric, A Cognizant Digital Business

September 24, 2018, Eduardo and Pol were students together

'Genuine expert' is the phrase that comes to mind when I think about Pol. I had the privilege of studying with him for more than a year.

I was particularly impressed by Pol's ability to handle even the toughest programming projects effortlessly. Besides Pol is proactive, result oriented, responsible and technically sound person and he is always ready to put all his energy and time to get the job done.

Any company would be lucky to work with Pol together.



Alberto Vila

Director en Institut Tecnològic de Barcelona

September 29, 2020, Alberto was Pol's mentor Pol es un persona que se involucra en profundidad. Tiene una alta capacidad resolutiva y se preocupa por obtener un resultado que satisfaga plenamente. Demuestra una seriedad y profesionalidad que contrastan con su juventud.



Oscar Garcia Pañella, PhD

Senior PhD / Gamification Consultant (Cookie Box) / Director (ENTI-UB, IEBS) / Gamejam Summit / EU InterSTEM

September 18, 2019, Oscar was Pol's mentor Pol was my student within the Algebra class of the Videogame Development degree in ENTI-UB. He showed a great interest in everything we would analize and discuss while delivering great showcases in all his assignments. There was no formula difficult enough so that he couldn't implement it in a nice and elegant way. Therefore I truly recommend Pol because he is a focused and passionate about what he does. He knows how to get practical results from theoretical backgounds.



Eric Garcia Reverter Developer en Surreal Boost

September 13, 2019, Pol worked with Eric in the same group Pol is one of the most tenacious person I have ever met. He has a huge Intuition for finding solution to any problem.

Undoubtedly, what most surprises me about him is the mysterious ability he has to get great ideas out of nowhere. Not only he is a solution detector, but also of opportunities and creative decisions.



Manel Taboada

Escuelas Universitarias Gimbernat (Adscritas a UAB y UC) - PhD in Computing, Expert in Training and Project Management

September 3, 2019, Manel was Pol's teacher My first contact with Pol was in the development of a teamwork seminar during his internship at SIGMA. During the session, of just 3 hours, I had the opportunity to realize how he was one of the students who stood out in the group of participants, which was 20 students of Vocational Studies (Formación Profesional).

As a result of his outstanding stay in SIGMA, he was distinguished with 1 of the 4 SIGMA-GIMBERNAT scholarships, that covered the 100% of the cost of the Postgraduate in IT Project Management, a course carried out in the Escuelas Universitarias Gimbernat (Adscritas a la UAB), a degree that i have the honour of coordinating. And precisely its passage through the Postgraduate has allowed us to know Pol more closely. And really the opinion of the entire teaching team is unanimous: a committed student, who is not overcome by difficulties, and meticulous, who takes care of every last detail. Some very important fact is that Pol attended the postgraduate combinedly with the 1st year of a University Degree

....

I have not had the opportunity to interact with him on a professional level, but I am convinced that he will follow the same model / style.

Congratulations Pol, I wish you a great professional future.